Analyst at Deloitte USI | NIT Trichy 2015-2019 | Cleared CFA® Level 1

+91-9500415228

Proactive and diligent individual, with excellent communication and interpersonal skills. Possess keen interest in research and analysis, with an ability to produce well researched and organized reports. Fluent in preparing presentations and spreadsheet models with substantial experience in computation and programming. In a constant pursuit to broaden my business acumen and financial knowledge.

# **EDUCATION**

#### CFA®Level1Passed

Chartered Financial Analyst® Institute

Jan 2020 - Present

· Curriculum:

Ethical and professional standards, Quantitative methods, Economics, Financial reporting and analysis, Corporate finance, Equity Investments, Fixed Income, Alternative investments.

### Finance and Quantitative Modeling for analysts

Wharton Online and Coursera

Jan 2020

Curriculum:

Fundamentals of Quantitative Modelling, Introduction to Spreadsheets and Models, Financial Acumen for Non-Financial Managers, Introduction to Corporate Finance

# Bachelor of Technology: Electrical and Electronics Engineering with minors in Management

National Institute of Technology Tiruchirappalli - Tiruchirappalli, TN July 2015 - May 2019

- CGPA: 7.28
- · Coursework Includes:

Mathematics, Basics of Programming, Numerical Methods for Electrical Engineers, Marketing Management, Data Structures and Algorithm, Financial Management.

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Member of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Association of NIT Trichy

#### Senior School Certificate Examination (CBSE)

The Velammal international School

April 2014

· Percentage: 91.8%

# **ORGANISATIONS**

## **Treasurer**

Festember, NIT Trichy, Tiruchirappalli, TN

Dec 2017 - Dec 2018

- Planned and managed an annual budget of over 30 lakhs INR, tracking expenses and investigating discrepancies to maintain optimal controls
- Worked with executive members to create annual budget and tracked actual expenses against projected expenses
- · Accurately documented all transactions and prepared a year end report

### **Marketing Manager**

Pragyan, NIT Trichy, Tiruchirappalli, TN

Mar 2017 - Dec 2017

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Identified new targets, developed new business opportunities and pitched for sponsorship
- Participated in brainstorming sessions to find new avenues to associate with target companies

# INTERESTS

Reading | Philosophy | Quizzing | Football

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Business Technology Analyst**

Deloitte USI, Bengaluru, KA

Aug 2019 - Present

- Worked with a team responsible for developing a web-based solution allowing users to generate real time price quotes.
- · Underwent training in core Java and SAP Hybris.
- · Participated in requirement meetings to understand business needs

# **Investment Banking Intern**

Pears Capital Limited, Chennai, TN

Apr 2018 - May 2018

- ${\boldsymbol \cdot}$  Performed valid and accurate market research for various clients
- Gathered and arranged research data to create representative graphs and charts highlighting results for presentations
- Collected data on competitors, consumers and marketplace and consolidated data into presentations and reports

#### **Equity Research Analyst Intern**

Divya Śwaroopa Financial Śervices, Chennai, TN Dec 2017 - Jan 2018

- Analyzed stocks using technical indicators for buy and sell recommendations
- Read financial publications to remain informed about trends affecting market conditions
- Marked charts and graphs to record results and prepared and delivered presentations

# **CERTIFICATES**

- · SAS® Programming 1: Essentials
- $\bullet$  Excel for corporate finance professionals LinkedIn learning  $\! \mathbb{R} \!$
- Financial Forecasting with big data Project management Institute®
- R for Data Science Udemy®

# **SKILLS**

- Business correspondence
- R Studio
- SAS
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft PowerPoint

# **PROJECTS**

# Identifying distribution of returns of stocks with required metrics

- A R script that gets inputs from the user and identifies stocks with the required parameters in a given time-frame.
- The script further calculates the return of the selected stocks in the given time-frame and displays a chart showing the return distribution.

# Study on consumer behaviour towards adopting renewable energy technologies in India

- A study analyzing the adoption of Renewable technologies in rural and urban areas in India.
- The study aimed at identifying key constructs and tried to draw inferences from the obtained results.